A Guide to the Food Advertisement Collection, 1894-1962
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Food Advertisement Collection, 1894-1962
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2017-020
0.3 Cubic Feet 1 box
The Food Advertisement Collection consists of single page advertisements for a variety of food products, largely pulled from magazines. Items dates from 1894 to 1962, with the majority from the 1910s-1940s.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Food Advertisement Collection was purchased by Special Collections in June 2016.
Scope and Content
The Food Advertisement Collection consists of single page advertisements for a variety of food products, largely pulled from magazines. Items dates from 1894 to 1962, with the majority from the 1910s-1940s. Ads included are for baby foods, dairy products, cooking/baking items, and peanuts/peanut butter.
While not intentionally part of the collection, the verso sides of many ads feature additional advertisements for food, home, and domestic products.
Arrangement
When this collection was purchased, advertisements were largely organized by product or product type. During processing, some of these categories were broken down further. The collection is arranged by product/product type and by company/brand within each product. Each company/brand has its own folder, the contents of which are in chronological order.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials: Culinary Advertising Collections in Special Collections
Alice Ross Culinary Ephemera Collection (Ms2017-008). Finding aid available online.
Ballard and Ballard Company Collection (Ms2010-032). Finding aid available online.
Culinary Ephemera Collection (Ms2013-028). Finding aid available online.
Culinary Pamphlet Collection (Ms2011-002). Finding aid available online.
J. H. Filbert Inc. Collection (Ms2013-061). Finding aid available online.
LactAid, Inc., Collection (Ms2011-008). Finding aid available online.
National Biscuit Company Package Catalog (Ms2017-019). Finding aid available online.
National Biscuit Company Salesman's Collection (Ms2017-017). Finding aid available online.
Quality Chemical Company Collection (Ms2010-039). Finding aid available online.
Sweet 'N Low and Butter Buds Promotional Materials (Ms2012-058). Finding aid available online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Ann Hertzler Children's Cookbooks and Nutrition Literature Collection; Children -- Nutrition; Food Technology and Production; History of Food and Drink; Nutrition
- Baby Food, 1894-1947
  - Campbell's, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clapp's, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gerber's, 1934, 1942, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Heinz, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Imperial Granum, c.1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mellin's, 1894-1925, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Merrell-Soule Co., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Butter, 1930-1935
  - Land O' Lakes, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meadow Gold, 1931, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Swift's, 1930, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cheese, 1925-1952
  - Kraft, 1925-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pabst-ett, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cooking Oil, 1913-1930
  - Crisco, 1913-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mazola, 1920, 1924, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Snowdrift, 1926, 1928, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wesson, 1919-1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Ice Cream, 1935-1954
  - Borden, 1942, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sealtest, 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Margarine, 1920-1949
  - Delrich, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Good Luck, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Morris, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Nucoa, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Parkay, 1941, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Milk & Cream, 1903-1949, n.d.
  - Borden's, 1911-1949 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carnation, 1916-1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Highland Brand Evaporated Cream, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hipolyte Company, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Horlick's, 1928, 1930, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Libby's Evaporated Milk, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Pet Evaporated Milk, 1921-1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reddi-Wip, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Peanuts, 1924-1958
  - Curtiss, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Planter's, 1924-1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Peanut Butter, 1917-1926
  - Beech-Nut, 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Heinz, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Single Products, 1919-1962, n.d.
  - Diamond Walnuts, 1926, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dairy-General, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dixie Cups, 1919-1962, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - McLaren Real Cake Cones, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - National Association of Ice Industries, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Royal Baking Powder, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 41)